[Music]
Hey Hong Kong, it's great to have you
here.
Thanks for having I think since 2015 we
started our partnership and it has been
a very good 10 years or so. Yeah. So
thanks again for being the second guest
for our CEO interview. Yeah. So today
we're looking forward to a good
discussion with you. It's been nearly 10
years since we signed the partnership
agreement and during this period I think
we have seen our AUA saw in a phenomenal
way you know MFA from 0 to 750 million.
Yeah. So what milestones or achievements
stand out in particular to you in this
partnership?
It's an honor to be here. So for us just
nice manual life FA we are also
celebrating our 10 year anniversary this
year. So MFA I think in Singapore we
have grown to be a market leader in
terms of the FA space. So currently I
have about,300 reps but I think this
success won't be possible with uh
partnerships like with IFAS which we
have been partnering like you say for
the last 10 years. I think we are very
happy that IFAS is MFA is the largest
investment platform service provider. I
think together like you mentioned we
work together to build the
AUMumumumumumumumumumumumumumumumumumumum
to over 750 million but I think what
impresses me most is our partnership is
that I think if is really uh very
supportive in the digital front and
because of this I think our customers as
well as our reps are able to do all the
customer experience together in a more
efficient way under the the platform
provided by IFAS. Yeah, indeed. As I
said just now, the success has been
phenomenal and I think that in part
plays because of MFA's rather open
architecture model.
So, um I think MFA is stands out because
it embraces quite a lot of different
products. Yeah. So, I think on our
platform MFA uses almost all the
different products other unit trust,
bonds, ETFs, our cash solutions, our
manage accounts and so on. I believe
that for advisers to really provide
holistic planning, they also need to
advise across a variety of products and
tools. Actually, I'm also very happy to
add on to say that um IAS actually
awarded Manual Life FA uh to be the top
insurer uh IFAS platform for the last
three consecutive years. So, thank you
very much again.
Thank you for your support. Thank you.
Yeah. So, you have been in the industry
for quite a long time and I think you
have seen the industry the landscape
change quite significantly. So what are
the biggest shifts that you have
observed over these years?
The first one is probably the FA arena,
the FA space. So we recently saw the LIA
statistics. Uh the FA market share of uh
sales. This is on the insurance side. It
has grown uh leaps and bound I think
from uh the teens to now over 30%. So I
can see that the FA market uh or the FA
channel is playing a more active role in
Singapore in providing uh financial
services. Uh with that I think uh
because of how we like you mentioned
just now how we are a open architecture.
So we actually do uh insurance as well
as investment advisory. On that note uh
MAS or the regulatory front they also
put more emphasis on the wholesales
advisory process.
uh we t this term called uh
comprehensive financial planning uh as
well as a regular policy review. Uh this
is something that we want to do to make
sure that our our financial uh
representative will continue to engage
the customers and this is important
because with the advancement in digital
we are aware that customers are more
sophisticated they are more uh well read
well versed in both investment and
insurance solution. So I think all these
coming together we can see that there
will be uh the landscape is really
changing where uh doing a proper sales
advisory process is necessary to make
sure that our customers are well
informed about their decisions.
Indeed. Yeah. Just to share so when I
first started in the industry I think at
that time the FA channel was like a very
tiny portion right if you're looking at
the weighted premiums I believe that's
the term they use.
Yes correct.
I think it was less than 10% during
Yeah. And now I think FAS have risen a
lot more and they occupy a much bigger
market share.
Absolutely correct Vincent.
Yeah. So I think in the past also um FAS
usually focus more on insurance only and
when it comes to investments they
sometimes are known as like unit trust
advisor. Some people even call them that
but I think after all these years uh
things are really different now. um
right now they can advise so many things
and I in fact I think that they are they
are forced to be reckoned with and they
also compete quite strongly with your
even your private bankers.
That's correct because I think we we
like to think of ourselves as being able
to do a one-stop financial solutions
giving you advice both on insurance as
well investment.
Okay. Yeah. Agree. Yeah. So MFA has been
an early adopter of digital processes
and has embraced electronic submissions
and approvals with IFAS. For example,
account opening with IFAS can be done
now using Syncpass. So it's already
online and seamless. So what impact have
you observed from let's say adopting
digital solutions IAS uh particularly in
improving your efficiency and customer
experience.
So so let's start out with something
simple like account opening. uh it may
sound simple but uh thanks to sync pass
I think everything can be um uh
completed more digitally and that is
important because then that is a speed
to completion as well as there's lot
less prone to human error when it's done
digitally beyond account opening I think
MFA and IFAS we have collaborated and I
see there's a lot of more about 90% of
transaction right now is submitted
digitally and this definitely helped
both my financial uh representatives as
well as their clients to make sure that
we are able to complete a transaction uh
timely as well as very efficiently and
less error happening. So I think this is
very important for us to have this
efficiency coming together. So on our
side I think yeah we we have been very
happy that MFA has embraced all this uh
in a way it it just makes things more
efficient for both parties. Yeah
correct. So uh we are also looking at uh
incorporating AI into some of the back
end processes. So I believe that but we
are rolling AI out in a rather cautious
manner.
So probably sometime next year we will
roll out something for the B2B space. So
you can stay tuned for that.
Okay. Yeah. Okay. Thank you. That's very
important. Yeah.
How do you see the role of financial
advisor evolving over the next five
years?
One is in terms of the population we
have in Singapore. So as we are know uh
our we have uh maybe starting to have a
aging population where our age
demographics are getting older. Yeah. So
as well as our people are living longer
as well in general.
So I think for us besides the usual
financial advisory solutions that we
provide our people may want to be more
focused also on medical needs as well as
retirement needs because these are
probably two of the one that is uh on
top of people's mind. So just now you
asked about the role of our advisers how
they will can evolve in the next five
years. So is they can play a more active
role in advising all uh our clients on
on this few front. On that note um MES
collaborated with the industry
associations like LIA uh ABS and AFAS.
They also came out with a basic
financial planning guide to help
Singaporeans or anyone or residents of
Singapore to say hey what are the
different parts of uh the solutions that
you need to look for uh not just
investment and not just insurance and
within insurance of course all the
hospitalization as well as retirement.
So I thought that's very important uh
that our financial advisor will play
that role. I think second part of it is
actually what exactly you mentioned
about AI. So I think technology is
definitely here to stay. I think AI is
the biggest word uh the buzz word at the
moment and uh sometimes my financial
representatives are afraid of AI taking
over them. So I would like to reassure
them that actually is a opportunity to
complement each other because that's how
AI can help us do our work better and
make sure our we do comprehensive
financial planning as well as regular
policy review with the help of AI so
that our clients can make the best
decision.
We also see that uh clients are aging. I
mean we have quite a lot of the client
data on our database. So we see clients
are aging and uh their wealth is also
growing. So I think financial advisers
are it's quite timely for them to make
sure that they capture this part of the
market and I think another thing is on
uh handing over to the next generation
right because there's intergeneration
transfer of wealth yeah so over the next
5 years I also believe that um FAS um
they're going to be as I said just now
they're going to be a much stronger
alternative let's say compared to
private bankers and I think where FA
stand out even more is that they can be
much more digital totally flexible
compared to let's say uh private banks
or so. Yeah.
So how do you think that if can help MFA
stay ahead of these trends and let's say
continue to provide value to clients?
Manual life FA we are always looking for
financial solutions for our clients. So
of course I would love to continue to
collaborate with uh IFAS to come out
with innovative products uh so that we
can continue to excite our customers
with our proposition to give them uh
different offerings. That's number one.
Number two is what you mentioned just
now on uh operational efficiency. Uh I
think digitally I think our two
companies can even collaborate even
further to make sure that our two our
systems uh do talk to each other more
often. Exchange of data so that um data
security is there plus exchanges of data
so that we we as a two entity have a
win-win situation where our processes
and and data transfers are very
efficient. I think one thing that no one
would probably disagree is that the
administrative and paperwork has also
gone up tremendously over the years,
right? I think uh in part due to
increasing regulation.
Yes.
Yeah. In fact, I remember a long time
ago the factf find form was only just a
few a few pages. Yeah. I think now it's
one thick booklet, right? Something like
that for the whole industry.
A lot of terms and conditions
declaration required. Yes. Correct.
Yeah. So I think uh yeah if we can
streamline our processes you know both
system talk to each other more I think
we can help to reduce all this you know
uh administrative effort and focus more
on providing value to clients.
Yes agree.
So is there anything else that you think
we can look forward to
for MFA myself first? So MFA um I wanted
my our company to even grow even bigger.
Uh my dream is actually uh Manuel FA
will be the FA CHO of choice in
Singapore which means that clients want
to deal with us as well as uh people who
want to join us to be in manual life FA.
But I think this can only be possible
and this is what we have done in the
last 10 years is have a very good
business partner like IFAS to help us.
Uh we really collaborate together. I
know we have challenging times but we al
we will really sit down two management
team we will really sit down and um
trash out the different things together.
So I I really like this collaborative
effort and I hope to continue to work
with uh IFAS closely uh not just the
next 10 years but beyond. So so
hopefully that that will bring uh not
just value to my financial
representative uh but also to our
clients as well as to both companies
together.
Yeah. Thanks for your support all these
10 years. I think I think we couldn't
have gone both companies wouldn't have
gone so far in servicing reps and the
clients you know without without the
support.
So yeah, thank you again for joining
into this interview.
Yeah, thanks. Thank you.
Thank you very much. Thank you. Thank
you.
[Music]